Andrei Cioroianu

Craiova, Romania andrei.c.cioroianu@gmail.com

devsphere.com finchart.org linkedin.com/in/andrei-cioroianu

Summary

Senior Software Developer, Consultant, and Project Manager with over 25 years of professional experience in solving complex technical problems and managing the full life cycle of commercial products, custom applications, and open-source frameworks. I hold a Master of Science degree in Artificial Intelligence and have a passion for interactive data visualization and trading software development.

My core competencies include UI design/development, API design/implementation, software porting/migration from one platform/language to another, financial charts, technical indicators, algo-trading, and back-testing software. I have extensive experience using HTML5, Java, and .NET to build robust and user-friendly applications that meet the needs of traders and investors.

Experience

Founder and Senior Software Developer

Devsphere.com 2000 – Present

- Developed FinChart (<u>finchart.org</u>), a JavaScript charting library for trading platforms and financial websites. The library includes 80 technical indicators, 20 drawing tools, and many other features. It works on both desktop and mobile devices, and is based on JavaScript, D3, and SVG.
- Created trading platforms based on HTML5, Java, and .NET. Worked on financial charting, tools for technical analysis, trading Uis, and trading from the chart. Built a desktop product for back-testing and algo-trading, allowing users to develop trading strategies using either a visual editor or JavaScript.
- Ported Java software to .NET and Dart. Implemented API mappings, creating .NET and Dart
 equivalents of the Java APIs used by the ported software. These were subsets of the Java
 graphics, Swing, I/O, collections, etc., which were implemented in .NET and Dart.
 Redesigned desktop UIs to be responsive and to work on Web and mobile devices.
- Developed Java desktop and Java EE applications. Created websites and Web applications
 using JSP, ASP, and PHP. Created a Java framework for scalable XML parsing, mixing the
 SAX and DOM APIs. Implemented reusable software components, code generators, and
 other tools for improving developer productivity.

Used ChatGPT / Bing Copilot to generate code, scripts, and Web pages. Engaged in dozens
of conversations with this generative AI on various subjects, to gain a better understanding
of its capabilities.

Author of Java articles and books

Oracle, IBM, O'Reilly, IDG, Wrox Press 1998 – 2009

- Wrote over 40 articles published by Oracle Technology Network (OTN), IBM developerWorks, O'Reilly ONJava, IDG JavaWorld, and Java Developer's Journal. Coauthored Java XML Programmer's Reference and Professional Java XML published by Wrox Press.
- Invited by OTN editors In 2004 to contribute to Oracle's Mastering J2EE Application
 Development Series. The list of contributors also included Rod Johnson (Co-author of
 Spring Framework), Craig McClanahan (Creator of Struts), and best-selling authors such as
 Ted Neward and Hans Bergsten.

Software Developer

Freelancer

1994 - 2000

- Developed a CAD and 3D modeling product using Java 3D. Implemented the 3D graphics engine of a chess game running as a Java applet. Created Java desktop products based on Swing.
- Used C++ to build a 3D game and 3D demos. Used FoxPro to develop database applications. Used Turbo Pascal to build a UI framework and DOS utilities. Wrote a book on Turbo Pascal published by Teora.
- Used AutoCAD to create 2D diagrams. Used Autodesk 3D Studio to create TV spots.

Education

University of Craiova

Master of Science (MS), Artificial Intelligence (1997 – 1998)

University of Craiova

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science (1993 – 1997)

Skills

FinTech Enterprise Solution Design Trading Platform Development Artificial Intelligence (AI)

Financial Charts Generative AI

Cross-platform Development Java

Data Visualization Java Swing

2D/3D Graphics JavaServer Pages (JSP)
Algorithmic Trading JavaServer Faces (JSF)

Backtesting JavaScript
API Design Node.js
Software Porting D3.js
Project Management AJAX
Agile Methodologies XML
Software Development HTML5

Front-End Development Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG)
Web Development Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

Website Administration SQL
Programming Dart
Consulting PHP
Technical Writing / Documentation Python
Troubleshooting C#
Problem Solving C++

Analytical Skills

Attention to Detail

User Interface Design

Responsive Web Design

Version Control

Subversion

Linux

Windows